{"tossups": [{"question": "1. An author living in this country formed the \u201cSouth Wind\u201d literary group and wrote several works about economic migrants to this country in works like A Hand Full of Stars; that author is Rafik Schami. In this country, the Blank Agency, led by Theodor Blank, was responsible for rebuilding the army. Walter Heller restructured this nation\u2019s tax structure by increasing the cutoff for its top tax bracket, which has a marginal rate of 95 percent. Economic aid to this country was banned by JCS 1067, which was later repealed by JCS 1779, leading to the mass resignation of the (*) Morgenthau Boys. This country\u2019s economic miracle was overseen by Ludwig Erhard, the finance minister under chancellor Konrad Adenauer. For 10 points, name this nation which faced another economic challenge when it was reunited with its eastern neighbor after the fall of the Berlin Wall.", "answer": "West Germany [or the Federal Republic of Germany; or Bundesrepublik Deutschland; or FRG; or BRD; prompt on Germany] &lt;EM, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "2. A section of a poem titled for this word ends by imagining the \u201csilken skilled transmemberment of song\u201d before saying \u201cPermit me\u201d [this word] \u201clove, into your hands\u2026.\u201d This word titles a poem dedicated to Maxime du Camp that describes a \u201cchild obsessed with maps and engravings.\u201d The second section of a poem titled for this word opens discussing \u201cthe great wink of eternity.\u201d This is the [emphasize] last title word of a French poem that inspired an Henri Matisse painting, and which asks \u201cMy child, my sister\u201d to \u201cthink of the rapture\u201d and (*) accompany the speaker to a place with \u201cluxury, peace, and pleasure\u201d or \u201cluxe, calme et volupt\u00e9\u201d [loox kahlm ay voh-loop-TAY]. This word titles a series of six poems inspired by love for the Danish sailor Emil Opffer, all placed in the collection White Buildings by Hart Crane. For 10 points, The Flowers of Evil contains a poetic \u201cInvitation\u201d to what kind of journey?", "answer": "voyage [accept Voyages or \u201cThen Voyage\u201d or \u201cInvitation to the Voyage\u201d or \u201cL\u2019invitation au voyage;\u201d accept \u201cPermit me, love, voyage into your hands;\u201d prompt on loose synonyms such as journey or trip, asking for the French language equivalent] &lt;WA, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "3. A saying in this country about one of its minority groups states that if a dog licks your plate, you should clean it, but if a member of that group touches your plate, you should break it. This country\u2019s historic [emphasize] loss of the Najran region is reflected in the name of a secessionist group in one of its neighbors. People of African descent comprise this country\u2019s al-Akhdam minority. Many of its leaders belong to a sect named for the grandson of Husayn, which are distinguished from (*) Twelvers by the fact that they reject the infallibility of imams and are called Zaidis. This country is suffering from the worst cholera outbreak in recorded history thanks to a war with militants whose slogan is \u201cGod is Great, death to America, death to Israel, God curse the Jews, and victory for Islam,\u201d an Iranian-backed group targeted by Saudi intervention. For 10 points, name this nation in which the Houthis killed president Ali Abdullah Saleh in 2017.", "answer": "(Republic of) Yemen &lt;EM, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "4. The \u201cintention\u201d of a work titled for this place is studied in an article by Annabel Patterson, who read socio-political commentary into that work using Fulke Greville\u2019s testimony. A lengthy poem titled for this place was written in the Neapolitan dialect by Jacopo Sannazaro. This place is mentioned in a phrase whose meaning was preserved in England, but became part of an \u201celegiac tradition\u201d in France, according to an Erwin Panofsky essay. This region is the setting of a set of poems that declares (*) \u201cOmnia vincit amor\u201d or \u201clove conquers all.\u201d It\u2019s the setting of much bucolic [byoo-KAH-lick] poetry, including the Eclogues of Vergil and a poem about Pyrocles and Pamela dedicated to the Countess of Pembroke. For 10 points, name this setting of a romance by Philip Sidney, a region of Greece idealized as a pastoral paradise.", "answer": "Arcadia [accept \u201cEt in Arcadia ego\u201d; prompt on Greece] &lt;WA, Literary Legacy&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "5. A \u201cgreat man\u201d perspective was used by Arthur Herman in a 2001 best seller to explain how members of this group \u201cInvented the Modern World.\u201d Some studies of changes in long-term human capital cite how the kings of these people became the first to mandate universal education in 1496. The book Cracker Culture documents how the word \u201ccracker\u201d [emphasize] originally applied to these people. The Quaker Thomas Rawlinson created a paradigmatic example of (*) \u201cinvented tradition\u201d by popularizing a national dress associated with these people, according to Hugh Trevor-Roper. National conscience among these people greatly rose during a series of 19th-century \u201cclearances.\u201d The 18th-century \u201cEnlightenment\u201d of these people produced such works as A Theory of Moral Sentiments. For 10 points, name this tartan-wearing people who inhabit the Highlands.", "answer": "Scots [or Scottish people; accept Scotch-Irish or Scots Irish or clansmen; prompt on Celts or Celtic people; do not accept or prompt on \u201cIrish\u201d alone] &lt;WA, Historiography&gt;", "subcategory": "History British", "category": "History"}, {"question": "6. Dio Cassius writes that, while encamped near the Bagradas river, the soldier Regulus killed one of these animals and sent its skin to Rome. Onesicritus, a soldier of Alexander the Great, writes that the Indian lord Abisares kept two huge examples of these animals. The Latin word for these animals names the characteristic battle standard that was used by Sarmatians and Dacians, and later adopted by Roman cavalry. An event held at a place where one of these animals was believed to be killed was organized after a war in which the city of Kirrha was crushed by the (*) Amphictyonic League; later, that League defended that site with the backing of Philip II Macedon in the Third Sacred War. One of these animals with feline forelegs called a mu\u0161hu\u0161\u0161u [moosh-HOOSH-shoo] is depicted in gold on the Ishtar Gate. Thebes\u2019 founder Cadmus supposedly sowed the teeth of, for 10 points, what type of creature that names the Pythian games?", "answer": "dragons [or draco; accept snake or serpent or serpens on python; prompt on reptile] &lt;WA, Ancient History&gt;", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "7. 80,000 words of this novel were highlighted to re-create the text of the drug trafficking expos\u00e9 Fari\u00f1a in order to subvert a recent publication ban. In this novel, a man is found dead lying on a table with a note saying \u201ca foolish and ill-advised curiosity has robbed me of my life.\u201d In one of its episodes, two Benedictine monks are stripped of their clothes after they are accused of transporting a princess in a coach. In a digression in this novel that mimics the Patient Griselda story and is set in (*) Florence, a man tests the fidelity of his wife by asking his friend Lothario to seduce her. This novel\u2019s protagonist, who imagines seeing \u201cthirty or forty giants\u201d on a plain, is forced to retire from his new job for a year after losing a fight to the Knight of the White Moon. For 10 points, name this novel by Miguel Cervantes.", "answer": "Don Quixote [or The Ingenious Gentleman Don Quixote of La Mancha or El ingenioso hidalgo Don Quixote de la Mancha] &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "8. This story twice refers to the priest Jonas Ramus, who is the source of \u201cthe anecdotes of the whales and the bears.\u201d The translations of this story by Maurice Blanchot and Charles Baudelaire both omit the diaeresis in its title. A speaker in this story recalls how an \u201cold school-master of the district\u201d taught him the meaning of the words \u201ccylinder\u201d and \u201csphere.\u201d This story\u2019s epigraph, which states that the works of God \u201chave a depth in them greater than the well of Democritus,\u201d is altered from an essay by Joseph Glanville. Its central encounter, which causes a man\u2019s (*) \u201craven-black\u201d hair to turn white, takes place between Lofoden and Moske, where a man loses his brother but lashes himself to a water-cask, survives a series of gyrations, and is picked up by a boat. For 10 points, name this Edgar Allen Poe story in which a Norwegian sails into the title storm.", "answer": "\u201cA Descent into the Maelstr\u00f6m\u201d &lt;WA, Short Fiction&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "9. During this author\u2019s interview with a world leader, Pierre Daru brought up this author\u2019s translation of Voltaire\u2019s Mahomet, to which the world leader responded \u201cThat is an awful play.\u201d This author\u2019s poem \u201cThe Metamorphosis of Plants\u201d drew on his own scientific treatise of the same name. After he proposed to a 17-year-old girl at age 72 and was rejected, this author wrote the lines \u201cThey urged me to those lips, with (*) rapture crowned / Deserted me, and hurled me to the ground.\u201d Ludwig Wittgenstein\u2019s Remarks on Colour expands on ideas from this author\u2019s treatise Thoughts on Colour. This author of the \u201cMarienbad Elegy\u201d worked for the Duke of Saxe-Weimar, who ennobled him after he wrote about a youth who kills himself with a pair of pistols. For 10 points, name this creator of Young Werther.", "answer": "Johann Wolfgang von Goethe &lt;WA, Authors/Bios&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "10. When asked if she acted in any movies, a character in this play responds that she declined many offers because \u201ccinema is a shallow art\u201d since it has no fourth dimension. This play\u2019s main conflict is inspired by the \u201cGreat Drumsheugh Case\u201d described in William Roughead\u2019s book Bad Companions. Some schoolgirls in this play secretly pass around a copy of Th\u00e9ophile Gautier\u2019s novel Mademoiselle de Maupin between themselves. A girl in this play overhears a conversation in which a woman is accused of being jealous of (*) Dr. Joe Cardin. Towards this play\u2019s end, a woman confesses to another that she has loved her \u201cthe way they said\u201d and commits suicide after acknowledging that Mary Tilford\u2019s rumor about her may have been true. For 10 points, name this play about the purported lesbian relationship between the teachers Karen and Martha, written by Lillian Hellman.", "answer": "The Children's Hour  &lt;SB, Drama&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "11. A law regulating this profession was passed on the recommendation of the Bell Commission, led by Bertrand M. Bell. Licensure for members of this profession was challenged in a class-action lawsuit brought by Paul Jung. The UAPD and CIR are labor unions representing members of this profession. A report by the Carnegie Foundation\u2019s Abraham Flexner reformed the training of people in this profession. A case leading to a law regulating this profession was the subject of the first aired episode of Law and Order. Two members of this profession, Luise Weinstein and Gregg Stone, were charged with murder after an 18-year-old girl named (*) Libby Zion died, leading to the adoption of an 80-hour work week for members of this profession. For 10 points, name this profession ostensibly represented by the American Medical Association.", "answer": "physicians [or doctors; accept reasonable equivalents] &lt;EM, US History&gt;", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "12. Description acceptable. A set-up for one use of this tactic involved sending a poem asking \u201cWhy then not be content and stop the war?\u201d\u00a0to Yu Zhongwen and Yuwen Shu. Chen Guofu suggested that Chiang Kai-Shek use this tactic against the Japanese in 1938 during the Battle of Wuhan. Zhao Yingcheng recorded a four-month siege in 1642 in which this strategy was used both by the defenders and by rebels led by the \u201cDashing King.\u201d This strategy was employed against Yangdi\u2019s troops by Emperor Yeongyang\u2019s [yung-yahng\u2019s] general (*) Eulji Mundeok [uhl-jee moon-duck], who crushed Sui [sway] forces at the Battle of Salsu. When the Ming used this tactic against Li Zicheng, millions of peasants died and most of Kaifeng was destroyed. In 1672, the Dutch used this tactic to halt a French invasion and create a \u201cWater Line\u201d to rally behind. For 10 points, identify this tactic in which one uses a body like the Yellow River against the enemy.", "answer": "intentionally creating a flood [accept any answer involving a man-made flood, or logical equivalents such as river overflow until \u201criver,\u201d or anything about removing a dam; accept equivalents such as inundation of the enemy, or inventive terms like diluvian tactics; prompt on drowning] &lt;WA, World History&gt;", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "13. In a novel set during this war, the narrator remembers playing Big Bear and Little Bear with his father; that narrator observes the spectacle of a man who is publicly shaved, then beheaded. In a novel set during this war, the Pulitzer\u00a0Prize-winning Darrow and his assistant both have affairs with the photojournalist Helen. This setting of Tatjana Soli\u2019s The Lotus Eaters is also the location of a novel that begins with the line \u201cIt was a bad time\u201d and features the deaths of Frenchie Tucker and Bernie Lynn. That novel repeats that the title character has (*) left for \u201cgay Paree.\u201d A spy and veteran of this war is tortured by the \u201cman with no face\u201d and consults about a movie on it in The Sympathizer. This war is also the setting of a novel in which Sarking Aung Wan guides Paul Berlin through a series of tunnels. For 10 points, name this war, the setting of Going After Cacciato by Tim O\u2019Brien.", "answer": "Vietnam War &lt;JC, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "14. The scenery in one of these places causes a woman to imagine seeing her dead mother in white walking through it. A character who compares herself to a \u201cwild turkey\u201d argues whether 10 specific objects constitute one of these places in a Tony-winning play by Christopher Durang. In another play, the music of a Jewish band comes to a halt as a drunk man triumphantly announces his acquisition of one of these places in an auction on August 22nd. An author ironically violated his own (*) literary principle in a play titled for one of these places by having a gun brought on stage by Yepidokhov, who never fires it. That play titled for one of these places ends with the death on a couch of the elderly servant Firs while axes are heard offstage. Lopakhin orders workers to chop down, for 10 points, what title place of an Anton Chekhov play?", "answer": "cherry orchards [or Vishnevyi sad; prompt on estates or forests or thickets] &lt;WA, Drama&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "15. The idea that these things are created by groups of \u201cintense demanders\u201d is advocated by Zaller, Noel, and other members of a UCLA School named for them. E. E. Schattscheider famously said that a certain system is \u201cunthinkable save in terms of\u201d these entities. An argument for the formation of these entities that considers a three-by-three payoff matrix to show that they are \u201cendogenous\u201d was advanced by Thomas Schwartz and John Aldrich, the latter of whom wrote a book asking \u201cWhy\u201d these entities. A text named for these entities introduced the idea that organizations ruled (*) democratically inevitably tend toward rule by an elite, an idea called the Iron Law of Oligarchy; that book is by Robert Michels. Another thinker posited that systems with plurality rule tend to result in only two of these things. Duverger\u2019s law governs the number of, for 10 points, what entities?", "answer": "political parties [accept Why Parties?] &lt;EM, Phil/SS&gt;", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "16. A story set in this historical period records how a man locked three divination documents in a brass-bound coffer, leading to his king being cured. A king during this historical period legendarily took his eight best horses with him on a journey to meet the Queen Mother of the West. The [emphasize] rise to power of the rulers of this dynasty is depicted in The Investiture of the Gods, which depicts the execution of a queen who was also a nine-tailed fox named Daji. A legendary (*) nobleman from this dynasty was the first to teach that natural disasters can result from a ruler\u2019s errors, and is called the \u201cDuke\u201d of a place with the same name. The Classic of Poetry, also known as the Book of Odes, is dated to this dynasty. For 10 points, name this dynasty which went into decline during the Spring and Autumn Period, during which Confucius lived.", "answer": "Zhou dynasty [accept Duke of Zhou or Zhou Gong] (the first story mentioned is \u201cThe Brass-Bound Coffer\u201d) &lt;WA, HistInLit&gt;", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "17. This city is the setting of the most notable literary adaptation of the legend of the murder of Horwendil by Feng. This city is the western endpoint of the HH Ferry route, which traverses three nautical miles, and was entirely within one country\u2019s control before the Treaty of Roskilde. Eric of Pomerania constructed a fortress in this city called Krogen in order to effectively collect a fee of one rose-noble from ships travelling through a nearby strait, a duty called the (*) Sound Toll. A work set in this city\u2019s stronghold of Kronborg borrows its material from the third and fourth books of Saxo Grammaticus\u2019s Gesta Danorum and features a man who says \u201cThis above all: To thine own be self be true,\u201d and who later says \u201cO, I am Slain!\u201d after being stabbed behind a tapestry. For 10 points, name this Danish city whose castle is the setting of Hamlet.", "answer": "Elsinore [or Helsing\u00f8r] &lt;WA, Continental History&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "18. A speech given to the Chamber of Commerce in this decade compared a group of foreign leaders with \u201chalf-educated statesmen\u201d such as Tiberius Gracchus. Hugh Wilson replaced the man who gave that speech, ambassador William Dodd, who resigned. A statement named for a Secretary of State during this decade affirmed the principle of ex injuria jus non oritur and continued commitment to an \u201copen door policy\u201d in light of violations of the Nine Power Treaty. An amendment first proposed in this decade called for a (*) referendum on any declaration of war, and was named for Louis Ludlow. After an incident in China in this decade, the U.S. refused to recognize territory gained by aggression via the Stimson Doctrine, a response to Japan seizing land in Manchuria. For 10 points, name this decade in which foreign powers were angered by the Smoot Hawley tariff, worsening the Depression.", "answer": "1930s [prompt on 30s or thirties] &lt;WA, US History&gt;", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "19. An essay titled for this practice presents a theory of mythology in which the seven worlds of the Great Chain of Being correspond to seven categories of archetypal imagery. A \u201cparasitic\u201d view of this practice is argued against in the \u201cPolemical Introduction\u201d to a book titled for it. Raymond Williams is one of several leftist figures analyzed in a work titled for this practice \u201cand Ideology\u201d by Terry Eagleton. The \u201cprinciples\u201d of this practice are outlined in the magnum opus of I. A. Richards. A 1957 book titled for this practice consists of essays on its \u201carchetypal,\u201d (*) \u201crhetorical,\u201d \u201cethical,\u201d and \u201chistorical\u201d forms, and was written by a Canadian academic. Northrop Frye\u2019s magnum opus is titled after the \u201cAnatomy of,\u201d for 10 points, what academic practice, which has \u201cNew\u201d Variety that was practiced by Cleanth Brooks, and which involves judging literary works?", "answer": "literary criticism [accept Criticism and Ideology or The Anatomy of Criticism] &lt;WA, Essays/Crit&gt;", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "20. So-called \u201cCaspar-style surgery\u201d became widespread in this country after Caspar Schamberger served there. This country\u2019s first steam engine was built by the inventor of the myriad-year clock. Medical knowledge was brought to this country by a man who created an extensive catalogue of its flora and fauna named Philipp Franz von Siebold. A writer in this non-India country used the pen name \u201cold man from India\u201d and wrote a scientific manual called \u201cRed Hair Chitchat.\u201d In this country, (*) importation of books was curtailed after the Morrison Incident, in which a U.S. merchantman was fired upon. The \u201cDutch Learning\u201d movement in this nation drew on texts imported to a small island called Dejima. The Treaty of Peace and Amity after Commodore Perry\u2019s Black Ships appeared in, for 10 points, what nation that excluded foreigners during the Tokugawa Shogunate?", "answer": "Japan [or Nippon-koku or Nihon-koku] &lt;EM, Historical Sources&gt;", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "21. The largest example of these structures in the New World was discovered underneath the Church of Our Lady of Remedies by the Swiss explorer Adolph Bandelier. Five phases of additions are known for one of these structures in Uxmal, called \u201cof the Magician.\u201d Oiling operations in the 1960s damaged the example of these structures found in Complex C of La Venta. A legend holds that, after escaping a flood, the giant Xelhua [SHELL-hwa] created the large one of these structures in (*) Cholula. One of these structures is found at the end of the Avenue of the Dead. The shadow that descends one of these structures in Tin\u00fam represents the descent of a serpent into the earth. Large examples of these structures \u201cof the Moon\u201d and \u201cof the Sun\u201d dominate the city of Teotihuacan. For 10 points, identify this shape taken by many temples in Mesoamerica such as Chichen Itz\u00e1.", "answer": "Mesoamerican pyramids [or Mesoamerican step pyramids; prompt on temples or religious complexes by asking \u201cwhat shape is the temple built in?\u201d; prompt on mounds by asking \u201cwhat kind of structure is beneath the mound?\u201d] &lt;WA, Archaeology&gt;", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "22. This poet\u2019s lover forced a change of the verb \u201cmay\u201d to \u201ccan\u201d throughout one work, due to jealousy over an ex named May Bookstaver, a story that is related in Joan Retallack\u2019s essay on \u201cNot Not Reading\u201d this poet. This poet wrote \u201cFull well I know that she is there\u201d to begin a work that claims \u201cI think very well of Susan\u201d and laments \u201cI wish that I had spoken only of it all.\u201d The line \u201cLet me recite what history teaches\u201d ends a work by this poet that asks \u201cWould he like it.\u201d That poem, \u201cIf I Told Him,\u201d was a retort to a quip that this author would grow to resemble a (*) portrait. This author described substances like \u201cGlazed Glitter\u201d and \u201cA Carafe [kuh-RAFF], that is a Blind Glass\u201d in a collection divided into \u201cObjects,\u201d \u201cFood,\u201d and \u201cRoom.\u201d In the poem \u201cSacred Emily,\u201d she wrote \u201cRose is a rose is a rose is a rose.\u201d For 10 points, name this expatriate author of \u201cTender Buttons\u201d and lover of Alice B. Toklas.", "answer": "Gertrude Stein &lt;JC, Poetry&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "23. The last page of a work of \u201cbio-history\u201d about a character with this occupation notes that everything in the novel is true, except perhaps \u201cthe Maya-scene.\u201d In a novel, a character who took this job requests that Ata burn the walls of his bungalow down after contracting leprosy. After being asked if he can see his \u201cideal\u201d in the \u201cface of a satyr,\u201d a character with this occupation is stabbed behind in the ear by an friend who gets rid of his body, then goes to Lady Narborough\u2019s party. A character who eventually takes up this occupation has an affair with Blanche after (*) quitting his job as a trader in London. This is the job of the protagonist of Irving Stone\u2019s biographical novel Lust for Life, as well as Charles Strickland, the protagonist of W. Somerset Maugham\u2019s The Moon and Sixpence. For 10 points, name this occupation of Basil Hallward, who creates the title work of an Oscar Wilde novel about Dorian Gray.", "answer": "painters [prompt on artists or bohemians] &lt;WA, LongFic&gt;", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "24. A politician of this surname travelled the world to try to cure himself of what he thought was syphilis in 1895 and wrote a public letter stating \u201cUlster will fight, and Ulster will be right.\u201d That politician with this surname, who resigned after serving as Lord Salisbury\u2019s Chancellor of the Exchequer for several months, led a group of radical Tories he called the \u201cFourth Party.\u201d Both the play One Night in November and F. W. Winterbotham\u2019s The Ultra Secret claimed that a leader with this surname knew the target of Operation Moonlight Sonata, an attack on (*) Coventry, in advance. That man with this surname spent time in a Boer prison camp while working as a journalist for The Daily Mail and won the 1953 Nobel Prize in Literature for The History of the English-Speaking Peoples. For 10 points, give the surname of the Prime Minister who led Britain during most of World War II.", "answer": "Churchill (Winston and Randolph) &lt;WA, British/Other History&gt;", "subcategory": "History British", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": []}